Register of the Gann-Duignan Papers, 1911-2003
Hoover Institution Archives
- Incremental correspondence, 1965-2002
  - Schutte, Gerhard, 1986 (Box-folder 85: 6)
  - Sebald, Peter, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 85: 7)
  - Shain, Barry, 1984 (Box-folder 85: 8)
  - Shao, John, 1984 (Box-folder 85: 9)
  - Shapiro, David, 1986 (Box-folder 85: 10)
  - Showalter, Dennis, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 85: 11)
  - Shtromas, Aleksandras, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 85: 12)
  - Smith, Clarence G., 1985 (Box-folder 85: 13)
  - Springborg, Robert, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 85: 14)
  - Symonds, Richard, 1984 (Box-folder 85: 15)
  - University Press of America, 1986 (Box-folder 85: 16)
  - Van Der Merwe, H. W., 1974-1978 (Box-folder 85: 17)
  - Vanneman, Peter, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 85: 18)
  - Verlagsburo, Heinrich Seewald, 1987 (Box-folder 85: 19)
  - Weinberg, book dealer, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 85: 20)
  - Weisman, Carlos, 1986 (Box-folder 85: 21)
  - Westview Press, 1987 (Box-folder 85: 22)
  - Woodward, Calvin A., 1984 (Box-folder 85: 23)
- Incremental speeches and writings, 1954-2002
  Includes manuscripts, typescripts, and printed copies of collaborative and individual writings of Gann and Duignan. Includes supporting material such as correspondence, notes, and reviews.
  - Alphabetical file I, 1965-1991
    Includes correspondence, contracts, reviews (praise file), research material, and supporting material for revisions and translations. Includes several typescripts, although the majority of the file contains supporting material for writings.
    - 1980 Middle East articles, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 85: 24)
      Includes typescripts of "The Cape Route," "The World Council of Churches," Red Star Ascendant?" "Who Caused the Energy Crisis?" "The Middle East in World Strategy," and "Iran Next?"
    - ACLU (American Civil Liberties Union), 1987-1989 (Box-folder 85: 25)
    - Africa and America: Reciprocal Impacts, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 85: 26-29)
      Possibly an alternate title for The United States and Africa: A History
    - Africa and the Communist World, 1976 (Box-folder 85: 30)
    - Africa Between East and West, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 85: 31)
    - Africa South of the Sahara, new edition for Tafelberg, 1982 (Box-folder 85: 32)
    - African Proconsuls and Rulers of British Africa, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 85: 33)
    - African Studies Committee, 1991 (Box-folder 85: 34-35)
    - Americans in Black Africa up to 1865, 1965 (Box-folder 86: 1)
    - "The Birth of An Atlantic Community", 1985 (Box-folder 86: 2)
    - "Birth of a Plural Society", 1980-1981 (Box-folder 86: 3)
    - Burden of Empire, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 86: 4)
    - Colonialism in Africa, 1870-1914, 1969-1982 (Box-folder 86: 5)
    - The Comstock Club, 1989 (Box-folder 86: 6)
    - Economics of Africa Since Independence, 1983 (Box-folder 86: 7)
      Proposal for a companion volume to Government and Politics in Sub-Saharan Africa Since Independence
    - The Hispanics in the United States: A History, 1975-1987 (Box-folder 86: 8-13)
      Includes op-ed typescripts and research files
    - Hoover African Colonial History Series, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 86: 14)
    - Hoover books on Africa by various authors, 1974-1980 (Box-folder 86: 15)
    - Huggins of Rhodesia and A History of Northern Rhodesia, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 86: 16)
    - "Illegal Aliens -- Curse or Blessing?", 1981 (Box-folder 86: 17)
    - The Middle East and North Africa: The Challenge to Western Security, 1981 (Box-folder 86: 18)
    - Negatives for letterhead, undated (Box-folder 86: 19)
    - Regan and Bush African Panel and praise file, 1980 (Box-folder 87: 1-3)
    - Reviews (praise file)
      - Colonialism in Africa, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 87: 4-7)
      - Defense of Western Europe, 1987 (Box-folder 87: 8)
      - From Protest to Challenge, edited by Gwendolen Carter and Thomas Karis, 1973-1987 (Box-folder 87: 9)
      - "Guerrillas in History", 1972 (Box-folder 87: 10)
      - "A Guide to Research and Reference Works on Sub-Saharan Africa", 1973-1976 (Box-folder 87: 11)
      - Hoover Colonial Studies Series, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 87: 12)
      - "Index Africanus" by J. O. Asamani, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 87: 13)
      - Israel, 1980 (Box-folder 87: 14)
      - The Library of the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 87: 15)
      - The Middle East and North Africa: The Challenge to Western Security, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 87: 16)
      - Miscellaneous, 1963-1981 (Box-folder 87: 17-18)
      - Native Administration in British Colonial Africa, with introduction by A.H.M. Kirk-Greene, undated (Box-folder 87: 19)
      - Politics and Governments in African States, 1960-1985, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 87: 20)
      - Rebirth of the West, undated (Box-folder 87: 21)
      - The Rulers of Belgian Africa, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 87: 22)
      - The Rulers of Belgian Africa (Contd.) (Box-folder 88: 1)
      - The Rulers of British Africa, 1870-1914, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 88: 2)
      - The Rulers of German Africa, 1884-1914, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 88: 3)
      - "South Africa: War, Revolution, or Peace?", 1978-1982 (Box-folder 88: 4)
      - Wilson, Evan, Decision on Palestine, 1980 (Box-folder 88: 5)
    - Revival of Europe, 1985 (Box-folder 88: 6)
      Includes letter from Alfons Heck
    - Rulers of German Africa, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 88: 7)
    - "South Africa's Future: War Revolution, or Peace", 1989 (Box-folder 88: 8)
    - "Soviet Strategy and South Africa", 1987 (Box-folder 88: 9)
    - Strategic Studies, 1981 (Box-folder 88: 10)
    - "The Struggle for Zimbabwe", 1980-1982 (Box-folder 88: 11)
    - The United States and Africa: A History, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 88: 12)
    - The United States and the African Slave Trade, 1619-1862, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 88: 13)
    - United States and Canadian Publications on Africa, 1961 to 1964, Hoover Bibliographic Series, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 88: 14)
    - "United States Trade and South Africa," testimony of Gann, 1982 (Box-folder 88: 15)
    - War and Strategic Studies Program, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 88: 16)
    - Western European Revival Project, 1985 (Box-folder 88: 17)
    - Why South Africa Will Survive, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 88: 18-23)
  - Alphabetical file II, 1968-2002
    Includes correspondence, reviews, and typescripts.
    - "Africa: What Needs To Be Done?" United States in the 1990s, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 135: 1)
    - Africa and the World, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 135: 2-3)
    - Amazon.com, 1998 (Box-folder 135: 4)
    - Africa Between East and West, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 135: 5)
    - "Aid, No, Trade, Yes", 1994 (Box-folder 135: 6)
      Includes typescript
    - American Foreign Policy Series, 1984-1991 (Box-folder 135: 7)
    - "Bilingual Education: A Critique", 1998-2001 (Box-folder 135: 8-9)
    - Blyden, Nemata, 2000 (Box-folder 135: 10)
    - Burden of Empire, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 135: 11)
    - Cambridge Press, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 135: 12)
    - "The Cold War: End and Aftermath", 1996 (Box-folder 135: 13)
    - Communism in Sub-Saharan Africa: A Reappraisal, 1994 (Box-folder 135: 14)
    - Contemporary Europe and the Atlantic Alliance: A Political History, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 135: 15)
    - Contemporary Europe and the Atlantic Alliance: A Political History (Contd.) (Box-folder 136: 1)
    - "The Dangers of Multiculturalism", 1995 (Box-folder 136: 2)
    - Defense of Western Europe, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 136: 3-6)
    - Deutch, R. "On Duignan and Gann", 1984, undated (Box-folder 136: 7)
    - Digital Library Project, 1999 (Box-folder 136: 8)
    - Drachkovitch Festschrift, 1993 (Box-folder 136: 9)
    - Economics of Western Europe, Elliot Zupnick, 1985-1991 (Box-folder 136: 10)
    - Encyclopedias article typescripts and correspondence, 1993-2001 (Box-folder 136: 11-13)
    - Encyclopedias article typescripts and correspondence (Contd.) (Box-folder 137: 1)
    - "The End of World War II and the Beginning of the Cold War", 1995 (Box-folder 137: 2)
    - Friedman essay, undated (Box-folder 137: 3)
    - From Protest to Challenge: A Documentary History of African Politics in South Africa, 1882-1964, edited by Gwendolen Carter and Thomas Karis, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 137: 4)
    - "The Future of South Africa: Will it be Violent or Peaceful," speech by Duignan to Costock Club, 1990 (Box-folder 137: 5)
    - Germans, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 137: 6)
    - Handbook of American Resources for African Studies, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 137: 7)
    - Handouts on Africa, 1990-1998, undated (Box-folder 137: 8)
    - Handouts on Europe, 2001, undated (Box-folder 137: 9)
      Includes Seabourn cruise lectures
    - The Hispanics in the United States: A History, 1988-2001 (Box-folder 137: 10-13)
    - The Hispanics in the United States: A History (Contd.) (Box-folder 139: 1-2)
    - Hoover Institution Guide to Scholars, correspondence with Kiana Underwood, 2002 (Box-folder 139: 3)
    - The Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace: Seventy-five years of Its History, 1986-1997 (Box-folder 139: 4-5)
    - Hope for South Africa? and "The Future of South Africa", 1989-1992 (Box-folder 139: 6)
    - Immigration, 1995-2001 (Box-folder 139: 7-13)
      Includes materials for a conference on immigration and documents related to The Hispanics in the United States and revisions
    - Immigration (Contd.) (Box-folder 140: 1-3)
    - Independent Review, 2000 (Box-folder 140: 4)
    - Knoll, The Rulers of German Africa, 1995 (Box-folder 140: 5)
    - "The Library of the hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace", 1998-2001 (Box-folder 140: 6-7)
    - "Lift Sanctions on South Africa", 1991 (Box-folder 140: 8)
    - "The Marshall Plan: Fifty Years After", undated (Box-folder 140: 9)
    - NATO: Its Past, Present, and Future, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 140: 10)
    - NATO: Its Past, Present, and Future (Contd.) (Box-folder 141: 1)
    - NATO op-ed, 1998 (Box-folder 141: 2)
    - New Europe lectures of Duignan, University of California, Santa Barbara, 1996 (Box-folder 141: 3)
    - Political Correctness: A Critique, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 141: 4)
    - Politics and Government in African States 1960-1985, edited by Duignan and Robert H. Jackson, 1982-1989 (Box-folder 141: 5-7)
    - Politics in Western Europe, edited by Duignan and Gerald A. Dorfman, 1984-1992 (Box-folder 141: 8-10)
    - Questia, 2000 (Box-folder 141: 11)
    - The Rebirth of the West, 1989-2000 (Box-folder 142: 1-4)
    - Recovery of Western Europe, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 142: 5-6)
    - Roye, Edward James article for American National Biography, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 142: 7)
    - The Rulers of Belgian Africa, 1884-1914, 1993 (Box-folder 142: 8)
    - The Stanford Report, 1995-2000 (Box-folder 142: 9)
    - "Stay Out of Bosnia", 1995 (Box-folder 142: 10)
    - "The U.N. After Fifty Years," typescript, undated (Box-folder 142: 11)
    - "The U.N.: Reform It", 1995 (Box-folder 142: 12)
    - U.S. after the Cold War, 1996 (Box-folder 142: 13)
    - The United States and Africa, 1984-2001 (Box-folder 143: 1-3)
    - The United States and the New Europe, 1990-1998 (Box-folder 143: 4-6)
    - The United States in the 1990s, 1988-1989, 1997 (Box-folder 143: 7)
    - Why South Africa Will Survive, 1991 (Box-folder 143: 8)
    - "World War II and Europe", 1995 (Box-folder 143: 9-10)
    - "World War II and the Beginning of the Cold War", 1996 (Box-folder 143: 11)
    - "The Yugoslav Imbroglio" from NATO: Its Past, Present, and Future, 1999 (Box-folder 143: 12)
  - Chronological file, 1954-2002
    Includes typescripts, manuscripts, and printed copies of collaborative and individual works of Gann and Duignan, arranged by date of publication.
    - Untitled typescripts, undated (Box-folder 175: 1-2)
    - Africa lectures, undated (Box-folder 175: 3)
    - "Africa: Mirage and Reality," Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 175: 4)
    - "Africa: The Real and the Stereotype," speech, undated (Box-folder 175: 5)
    - "Africa: Prospects and Problems," Duignan, undated (Box-folder 175: 6)
    - "Africa: What Needs to Be Done?" Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 175: 7)
    - "African Future," United Nations Association, speech most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 175: 8)
    - "African Historiography Lecture I", undated (Box-folder 175: 9)
    - "African History," lectures most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 175: 10)
      See also Portuguese Africa/course lectures and African political, social, and economic problems
    - "African Problems," Peace Corp., speech, undated (Box-folder 175: 11)
    - "America, Another View," speech by Gann, undated (Box-folder 175: 12)
    - "America, Another View" and "What Is Right with America," speeches by Gann, undated (Box-folder 175: 13)
    - "An Analysis of the White Rhodesian Position," most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 175: 14)
    - "Angola Lecture," most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 175: 15)
    - "Anti Semitism: Right and Left," speech most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 175: 16)
    - "Apartheid - Past and Future," most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 175: 17)
    - "Arms and the Men in South Africa," Gann, undated (Box-folder 175: 18)
    - "Bilingual Education", undated (Box-folder 175: 19)
    - British economy, Duignan, undated (Box-folder 175: 20)
    - British in Africa, Duignan, undated (Box-folder 175: 21)
    - "British Military Achievement in World War II," speech to the Great War Society, most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 175: 22)
    - "The Case for the White Man," Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 175: 23)
    - "The Cold War in Africa", undated (Box-folder 175: 24)
    - "The Cold War in Africa" and "Soviet Strategy and South Africa," Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 175: 25)
    - Colonialism, undated (Box-folder 175: 26)
    - "Colonialism: An Appraisal," Duignan, undated (Box-folder 175: 27-28)
    - Conflict and Peacemaking in Southern Africa, undated (Box-folder 175: 29)
    - "Concepts and Realities of Imperialism," lecture, undated (Box-folder 175: 30)
    - "Development and Underdevelopment in Africa: South of the Sahara," Gann, undated (Box-folder 175: 31)
    - Dissent on Colonialism, undated (Box-folder 175: 32)
    - "Don't Get Involved," Duignan, undated (Box-folder 175: 33)
    - "The East African Campaign," most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 1)
    - "East-West Rivalry in Southern Africa", undated (Box-folder 170: 2)
    - "EEC and Maastricht," Naval Command College, speech most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 3)
    - "The Emergence of the Northern Seafarers in the 17th Century", undated (Box-folder 170: 4)
    - "The English Disease: The Outlook for Britain," Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 5)
    - European recovery speeches, most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 6)
      Includes Tower Talks
    - "European Recovery," most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 7)
    - "Fall of Two Empires," speech most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 8)
    - "A Financial Fable", undated (Box-folder 170: 9)
    - "Franco-German Relations: The Changing Stereotypes," Haus Mitteleuropa Lecture, Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 10)
    - "The Future of South Africa," Duignan, undated (Box-folder 170: 11)
      See also The World and I file
    - "The Geography of Africa", undated (Box-folder 170: 12)
    - "German Colonialism Lecture," most likely by Gann, undate (Box-folder 170: 13)
    - "German and Japanese Wartime Empires," most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 14)
    - "German and Japanese World War II Empires," speech most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 15)
    - "Germans in African," speech, undated (Box-folder 170: 16)
    - "Gorbachev and Botha: Birds of a Feather," Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 170: 17)
    - "Governor Deukmejian: It's Illegal and Immoral to Divest," Duignan, undated (Box-folder 170: 18)
    - "The Great Game in Afghanistan," Duignan, undated (Box-folder 170: 19)
    - "Guerrillas in History," speech most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 20-21)
    - "Gulag in Angola," Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 170: 22)
    - Gunn High School speech, most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 23)
    - Haus Mitteleuropa Speaker Series, Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 24)
    - "Heine and the German - Jewish Enlightenment," speech, undated (Box-folder 170: 25)
    - "Hitler's Wehrmacht: Reflections on a Failure," Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 26)
    - "Hope for Africa", undated (Box-folder 170: 27)
    - "The Immigration Debate," Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 170: 28)
    - "Immigrant Factor in the U.S.," Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 29)
    - "Immigrant Factor in U.S. History," Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 30-31)
    - Immigration speech in French, most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 32)
    - "Intellectual Autobiography," Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 33)
    - "Invest in South Africa to Help Both Blacks and Whites," Duignan, undated (Box-folder 170: 34)
    - IR course introduction, Africa lectures, nuclear weapons/communism lectures, Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 35)
    - "Is German Democracy in Danger?" and "Is the Fourth Reich on Its Way?" Gann, undated (Box-folder 170: 36)
    - "Is It in the United States' Interest to Weaken the South African Economy?" Duignan, undated (Box-folder 99: 1)
    - "Islamic Fundamentalism: Is It a Threat to the West? To the Middle East?" lecture most likely by Duignan, undated (Box-folder 99: 2)
    - "Islamic Radicalism in the Middle East: A Survey and Balance Sheet", undated (Box-folder 99: 3)
    - Israel, undated (Box-folder 99: 4)
    - "Japanese Colonial Empire: Lecture on Comparative Aspects," Gann, undated (Box-folder 99: 5)
    - Lecture outlines of Duignan, undated (Box-folder 99: 6)
    - Lectures of Gann, undated (Box-folder 99: 7-8)
    - "Lessons of Normandy," Gann, undated (Box-folder 99: 9)
    - "Letter to a Graduate Student," Gann, undated (Box-folder 99: 10)
    - "Libya - A Threat to World Peace," Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 99: 11)
    - Marx lecture, undated (Box-folder 99: 12)
    - "Marx Is the Father of Both Socialism and Communism", undated (Box-folder 99: 13)
    - Middle East transparencies, undated (Box-folder 99: 14)
    - "Organization of African Unity (OAU)", undated (Box-folder 99: 15)
    - "Origins of Agriculture," most likely by Duignan, undated (Box-folder 99: 16)
    - Pan Africanism, undated (Box-folder 99: 17)
    - "Patterns in White and Black Multi-Racial Africa," Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 99: 18)
    - "Portuguese Africa," most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 99: 19)
    - "Portuguese Africa" and course lectures, Gann, undated (Box-folder 99: 20)
      Includes 10 lectures
    - "The Problem of Africa," Economic and Political Problems Within Nations, Duignan, undated (Box-folder 99: 21)
    - "Problems of African History," lecture by Gann, undated (Box-folder 99: 22)
    - "Problems of Development - Political Theories", undated (Box-folder 99: 23)
    - Reading list, undated (Box-folder 99: 24)
    - Regensburg lectures, Gann, undated (Box-folder 99: 25-26)
    - "Rhodesian Crisis," lecture, undated (Box-folder 99: 27)
    - "The Role of the White Man in Africa," Duignan, undated (Box-folder 98: 1)
    - "Russia, South Africa, and the Soviet 'Grand Design,'" Gann, undated (Box-folder 98: 2)
    - "Saddam Revisited", undated (Box-folder 98: 3)
    - "Should We Stop Trading with South Africa," Gann, undated (Box-folder 98: 4)
    - "South Africa Beyond Sanctions, Sermons," Gann, undated (Box-folder 98: 5)
    - South Africa lectures, Gann (Box-folder 98: 6-8)
    - "South Africa Revisited," Gann, undated (Box-folder 98: 9)
    - "South Africa: Time Running Out?" Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 98: 10)
    - "South Africa: What's to Be Done?" Duignan, undated (Box-folder 98: 11)
    - "Southern Rhodesia", undated (Box-folder 98: 12)
    - "Soviet Futures," speech most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 98: 13)
    - "The Soviet Future and World Peace," Gann, undated (Box-folder 98: 14)
    - "Soviet Strategy and South Africa," Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 98: 15)
    - "Sub-Saharan Africa", undated (Box-folder 98: 16)
    - "Terrorism," speech most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 98: 17)
    - Terrorism lectures, Gann, undated (Box-folder 98: 18)
    - "Tower Talk: Hispanics in the U.S.," speech most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 98: 19)
    - "Upheaval in Africa," most likely by Duignan, undated (Box-folder 98: 20)
    - United States and Africa to 1865, undated (Box-folder 98: 21)
    - "The United States and Africa" summary, most likely by Duignan, undated (Box-folder 98: 22)
    - "The United States and the New Russia," speech by Gann, undated (Box-folder 96: 1)
    - "United States, Russia, and Europe," speech most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 96: 2)
    - "The United States and the Slave Trade", undated (Box-folder 96: 3)
    - "The United States and South Africa," Gann and Duignan (Box-folder 96: 4-6)
    - "United States South African Relations," speech by Gann, undated (Box-folder 96: 7)
    - "United States: Stay Out of Rwanda, Zaire, and Such Like!" Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 96: 8)
    - "United States-USSR Conflict and Competition in Africa", undated (Box-folder 96: 9)
    - United States and USSR Strategy in the Middle East and Africa," Duignan, undated (Box-folder 96: 10)
    - "USSR and Third World," lecture to Jewish Community most likely by Gann, undated (Box-folder 96: 11)
    - "The Waffen SS", undated (Box-folder 96: 12)
    - "Washington Lecture: Soviet Union in Africa, 1921-1974", undated (Box-folder 96: 13)
    - "White Africans in Southern Rhodesia," Gann and Duignan, undated (Box-folder 96: 14)
    - "White and Black in Africa," most likely by Duignan, undated (Box-folder 96: 15)
    - "White Intellectuals, Settlers, and British Central Africa," Gann, undated (Box-folder 96: 16)
    - "White Regime May Be Much More Resilient Than Its Critics Assume," Gann, undated (Box-folder 96: 17)
    - "The White Settler in Rhodesia: Villain or Victim?" lecture notes of Gann, undated (Box-folder 96: 18)
    - "Will the Next World War Start in the Persian Gulf Over Oil?" Duignan, undated (Box-folder 96: 19)
      Alternate title, "Do We Face a Nuclear War Over Control of the Persian Gulf in 1985"
    - "The Working of Our Government," speech summary by Gann, undated (Box-folder 96: 20)
    - "The World-Wide Threat of Soviet Communism," Duignan, undated (Box-folder 96: 21)
    - "Zambia Lecture," Gann, undated (Box-folder 96: 22)
    - "The End of the Slave Trade in British Central Africa: 1889-1912," Gann, 1954 (Box-folder 96: 23)
    - "The Northern Rhodesian Copper Industry and the World of Copper: 1923-1952," Gann, 1955 (Box-folder 96: 24)
    - "Archives and the Study of Society," Gann, 1956 (Box-folder 96: 25)
    - "Early Jesuit Missionaries," Duignan, 1958 (Box-folder 96: 26)
    - "The Northern Rhodesia Journal as an Historical Source Book," Gann, 1958 (Box-folder 96: 27)
    - Conference on the Study and Teaching of History, lecture by Gann, 1959 (Box-folder 96: 28)
    - "Liberal Interpretations of South African History," Gann, 1959 (Box-folder 96: 29)
    - Witchcraft, Duignan, 1959, undated (Box-folder 96: 30)
    - Untitled typescripts and correspondence, 1960 (Box-folder 96: 31-32)
    - "The Africa Collections at Stanford University," Duignan, 1960 (Box-folder 96: 33)
    - "Central Africa's Heritage," Horizon article by Gann, 1960 (Box-folder 96: 34)
    - "A Different View of United States Policy in Africa," Gann and Duignan, 1960 (Box-folder 96: 35-36)
    - Rhodesia writings and research, circa 1960s (Box-folder 102: 1-2)
    - "White Settlers in Black Africa," most likely by Duignan, 1960 (Box-folder 102: 3)
    - "The Case for the White Man," Gann and Duignan, 1961 (Box-folder 102: 4)